Jeffrey Lewis | Software Developer

Denver, CO | lewis.jeffreyg@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/jeffrey-g-lewis | github.com/jgl3hb | jeffreyglewis.com

About Me

I'm an experienced software developer and entrepreneur with a background in sales and accounting. My expertise spans full-stack development, blending technical skills with practical experience. I strongly believe that technology has and always will move humanity forward.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, Ruby, Python, HTML, CSS
Libraries/Frameworks - Rails, React, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind
Database - MongoDB, PostgreSQL | Other - REST APIs, Git/Github, Tensorflow, OpenAl API

PROJECTS

Oracle-GPT | GPT Wrapper with Prompt Engineering

https://chatbot-psi-pink.vercel.app/

React.js, Node.js, Tailwind

- Developed a front-end GPT wrapper using React.js and styled with Tailwind
- Integrated the OpenAl Chat-GPT-3.5 API with prompt engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Founder

October 2023 – Present

Airglow | Denver, CO

- Developed computer vision algorithms and deep learning models to enable accurate facial and object recognition
- Led the ideation, design, and prototyping phases of a consumer-focused hardware/software system, combining facial and object recognition, GPT chat tools

Full Stack Software Developer

December 2022 – October 2023

HoundDog | Remote

- Implemented a message board with CRUD functionality within the Ruby on Rails application to enhance communication and efficiency for our clients' administrators
- Spearheaded the automation of an email/text notification system by leveraging Brevo and Twilio APIs
- Designed insurance forms from scratch with CSS and Bootstrap
- Participated in daily stand-ups and regular code reviews, and utilized Agile development with Jira

Insurance Specialist

November 2019 - August 2022

Unum Insurance Group | Remote

Calculated benefit payments using payroll, tax information and Excel

Accountant April 2018 – June 2019

ALPS Funds | Denver, CO

- Calculated net asset value for designated groups of mutual funds, ensuring accurate financial reporting
- Acquired proficiency in Excel-based accounting

Co-Founder

January 2017 - April 2018

BANKR App | Remote

- Led the design and UI/UX process for the app, from initial wireframes to prototypes
- Employed Agile development methods to translate designs into a functional app, overseeing the coding process to ensure alignment with design specifications and quality standards
- Collaborated with vendors to strategize and implement robust security systems and API integrations within the application

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Completed an intensive twelve-week program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, source control, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies

University of Missouri | Columbia, MO

2009

BS, Business Administration

Czech University of Life Sciences | Prague, Czech Republic

2008

International Business, Study Abroad